Aminata Kabba

Birmingham B17 | +447488530268 | aminata.kabba@outlook.com | www.aminatakabba.com

Frontend Web Developer / QA Test Analyst

ABOUT ME

I am a self taught web developer with experience using the most uptodate technologies . I developed my knowledge through a combination of self-led study, online courses, and building projects for clients . I am a fast learner and critical thinker with a growth mindset.

Currently working as a QA Test Analyst in an eCommerce company. I have got experience building web applications with responsive landing pages and enjoyable UX/UI, testing software and developing extensive reports for improvement.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Next, Leicester, Enderby: Trainee QA Test Analyst

OCT 2020 - CURRENTLY

- Working within a large team under the Agile Methodology.
- Develop a test plan with test requirements, test approach and scope of testing, technologies used and write a final report and review of the features functionality.
- Delegate with developers, POs, and PMs to ensure good quality software is being delivered
- Communicate quantitative and qualitative findings from test results to the development team.
- Identify areas for improvement to boost the product's efficiency.

University of Nottingham, Nottingham: Social media adviser

NOV 2019- JUN 2020

- Developing the social media platforms of the Students Careers and Employment Services at the University of Nottingham.
- I was working with a team of three people analysing and finding better ways of delivering excellent and engaging content for the students in the university.

EDUCATION

University of Nottingham, Nottingham: Engineering and Physical Sciences, Physics

SEP 2019-JUN 2020

- Computer methods, MatLab
- Advanced Mathematics, Algebra & Calculus
- Advanced Mechanics and Electromagnetism

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Working with JavaScript (ES6+) DOM and React is and React Native.
- Using frameworks/libraries such as Bootstrap, jQuery and Material UI.
- **Git / GitHub** source control and **npm** packages.
- Confident working in an **Agile** team providing updates and ensuring the highest standard of quality is provided in all work.
- Working with **Google Analytics** to ensure all features are working accordingly.
- Great at communicating remotely and updating my progress in projects.

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Strong interpersonal.
- Ability to respond to changing priorities and varying workloads.
- Ability to communicate in a concise and clear manner.
- A collaborative team player with time-management, communication and problem solving skills
- Confidence with learning new technologies and applying the knowledge to the company's needs.

PROJECT

Amazon Clone React App using JavaScript, React, Firebase and Material UI.

Random Recipe Generator using HTML, CSS, JavaScript React and Edamame API.

Wise Advice React App & RESTful API using JavaScript, React and API.

Messaging app using JavaScript, React Native and Expo

Portfolio: www.aminatakabba.com

Freelance website: www.amenta.co.uk

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages

- English
- Spanish
- Catalan
- French
- Soninke

Contact me

Portfolio: www.aminatakabba.com

Linkedin: Aminata Kabba

GitHub: https://github.com/aminatakabba